Vanessa Schultz

7915 Delbonita Avenue | Las Vegas, Nevada 89147 | 702-332-8237 | schultzvanessa@hotmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Marketing Professional with more than eight years of experience technical support, handling public relations, advertising, graphic design, and event coordination functions for several companies. Proven track record of exemplary performance, evidenced by having earned the Chairman's Award and Employee of the Month with most recent employer. Proficient with advertising through various social media platforms, including Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram.

LinkedIn Profile: www.linkedin.com/in/vanessa-schultz-61b63210

For samples of Graphic Design, WordPress and Facebook samples please visit:

http://schultzvanessa.wix.com/vanessasportfolio#!project01/c1mqf

https://vanessavialpando369gmail.wordpress.com/

https://www.facebook.com/positivephysicalandspiritualwellbeing

Writing samples can be provided by request.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Microsoft Office 2021 Suite	Premiere	YouTube
Adobe Creative Cloud 2021	Word Press	Tick Tok
InDesign	Dreamweaver	Quickbase MRM
Illustrator	Facebook	Workamajig
Photoshop	Instagram	Software Technician
After Effects	Twitter	

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Creative Media Specialist, XPSynergy, Las Vegas, Nevada

2019 - 2021

- Assist in the creation of digital, video, audio, social media and print content.
- Prepare and manage communications materials and strategies.
- Develop and maintain brand integrity across multiple platforms.
- Manage presence at virtual or in-person industry events, trade shows, and conferences.
- Manage media relations and develop contacts with media members, influencers, and community leaders.
- Manage budget for Creative Team and ensure compliance.

- Tech-savvy with strong computer and software navigation skills.
- Personal experience troubleshooting personal electronic devices (e.g., personal computers, smartphones, tablets), online downloads, transactions, applications, software and hardware issues.
- Technical proficiency in web-based software and ability to quickly support platform and product functionality.
- Strong customer service orientation with an upbeat, people-minded personality and a willingness to go above and beyond for every customer.
- Ability to communicate technical issues in non-technical terms to customers.
- Ability to analyze problems/inquiries and research all possible solutions using all available tools
- Outstanding active listening and comprehension skills.

Communications Specialist, Caesars Entertainment, Las Vegas, Nevada

2010 - 2017

- Wrote and proof read employee citywide communications for press releases, emails and printed advertisements for nine casinos which consisted of over 10,000 employees.
- Designed printed advertisements, maintained social media ad websites.
- Assisted the marketing departments with launching new guest programs and offers to employees with email blasts, printed advertisements, social media, texting programs and employee events.
- Volunteered and produced advertisements for community outreach programs, such as HERO and Code Green initiatives.
- Revamped back of house areas by having new branded wall wraps installed.
- Coordinated with Studio using or MRM submit design requests and receive printed advertisements.
- Sent all print requests to in-house print shops or outside print vendors.
- Implemented, advertised, coordinated and hosted employee events with the engagement teams.
- Ensured front of house and back of house employees viewed all current communications by posting them on informational bulletin boards, poster holders, table tents, banners and stand up signage.

Engagement Advisor, Caesars Entertainment, Las Vegas, Nevada

2009 - 2010

- Designed and copy wrote websites and print advertisements.
- Created, proof read and emailed out informational memos for employees and management.
- Maintained and edited video messaging.
- Launched and maintained social media and texting programs with Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest and Instagram and Hip cricket.
- Planned, coordinated and implemented employee events and programs. Created proposals and timelines for employee of the month programs, supervisor of the quarter, holiday parties, food drives, and other employee special events.

- Managed and implemented employee events and communications. Organized event setups and hosted events.
- Designed, copy wrote and proof read printed and website graphic materials.
- Maintained and edited all video messaging. Oversaw and staff, schedules, outside vendor purchases and budgets.

Graphic Designer, The LINQ, Las Vegas, Nevada

2005 - 2005

- Designed and copy wrote brochures, invitations, magazine ads, posters, and other advertisements for casino special events.
- Managed the company's library of art and ensured quality printing.
- Maintained website and social media.

EDUCATION

B.A., Communications, UNLV, Las Vegas, Nevada
GPA: 3.85 Emphasis in advertising, marketing, media and sales.
Associates Degree, Graphic Design, College of Southern Nevada, Las Vegas, Nevada

AWARDS

Chairman's Award – Innovation Employee of the Month